hey everybody welcome to this a1
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak and remember to sign up for
our one dollar listening practice
seminars at polyglossa.com
and download our free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about summer
for some of you it's summer now and for
others it's winter here where i live
it's the summer season now so first
let's talk about summer weather in most
countries
this is the hottest time of year in
cold countries summer is the only time
of year
when it's hot in tropical countries
there isn't much difference between the
seasons
but summer is definitely hot i really
like
hot sunny weather some people don't like
this weather
so they prefer other seasons how about
you do you prefer
hot or cold weather also in some places
summer is the rainy season where i live
now
it rains a lot in the summer i don't
like this
i grew up in southern california where
it doesn't rain a lot
so i'm used to blue skies and sunny
weather
for me rainy weather isn't fun i like to
go
outside and do activities but
it's hard to do this when it's raining
let's talk about some summer activities
that people
like to do during the hot summer days
many people like going to the beach
the water is usually warmer during this
season
so it's a good time to swim some people
like to lie on the sand and enjoy the
hot sun
but i don't do this i sometimes like
swimming at the beach but i definitely
don't sunbathe i get sunburned
very easily another thing that many
americans do
in the summer is have barbecues
this season is perfect for barbecues
because
you can spend the afternoon outside
with your family and friends the kids
can run around
and play while the adults relax
and talk and of course everyone enjoys
eating good
food at barbecues i love eating
hamburgers and hot dogs outside
on warm summer days also
many americans have swimming pools so
the summer months are a great time to
use them
when i was a kid my family always went
in the pool
during this time of year i have great
memories
of playing with my sister and my friends
in our pool
it's always fun to go in the pool during
the summer
people who don't have swimming pools can
go
to public pools in big cities
there are usually public swimming pools
where you can go
during the summer or during other months
one other popular summer activity in the
us
is camping summer is the perfect time to
go
camping because you don't get too cold
at night
usually people sleep outside in
tents when they camp so it's better to
do this
activity when it's warm i've camped in
the summer
and in the winter but it's definitely
better
in the summer a lot of people go hiking
when they camp
which is also better in the summer in my
opinion
alright now let's talk about summer
vacation
in the u.s children usually have a long
break from school
during the summer when i was in
elementary school
and middle school i had two and a half
months of summer vacation the school
year ended
in the middle of june and the next
school year began
in september this is a long break
i had time to do many things during
these months
many american children go to summer camp
during this break there are many types
of summer camps
where kids do fun activities learn new
things
and spend time outdoors i went to a few
sports summer camps when i was a kid
also many people travel during this
season
because children don't have to go to
school
summer is also a good time to travel
because
of the good weather but the bad thing
about traveling in the summer is that
many touristic places are crowded
at this time this means that there are
many
people there so i prefer
to travel during other seasons alright
now i'm going to ask you some questions
about the video
to see if you understood write your
answers in a comment down
below number one what's one summer
activity
number two where do people sleep when
they go
camping and number three what's
one bad thing about traveling during the
summer
okay before we go remember to sign up
for our one dollar listening practice
seminars
and download the listening time podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
and of course subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram i'll see you
next time
you